### AMJAD SEYEDI PhD Student

- amiadsevedi.github.io 🖸 github.com/AmiadSevedi @ sevedamiad.sevedi@umons.ac.be 🛘 +32 465 120 500
- Department of Mathematics and Operational Research, Polytech Mons, University of Mons, 7000, Belbium



### 🖺 BRIEFLY

I am currently pursuing my PhD on Matrix Theory and Optimization at the University of Mons under the supervision of Prof. Nicolas Gillis. Previously, as a graduate research assistant at the University of Kurdistan, I worked on representation learning with a focus on robustness and generalization. I also led the Algebraic Machine Learning Team (AML team), a group that explores fundamental methods in unsupervised machine learning. I have a Master's degree in Artificial Intelligence from the same university, where I worked with Dr. Parham Moradi and Dr. Fardin Akhlaghian on matrix factorization and low-rank approximation for various applications such as semi-supervised learning, multi-label classification, and recommendation systems. I also have an Associate and a Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering.

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Math: linear algebra, numerical analysis, optimization
- Applied Math: low-rank approximation, matrix factorization, tensor factorization
- Machine Learning: representation learning, deep learning, unsupervised learning
- Trustworthy ML: generalization, robustness, interpretability, fairness
- Applications: remote sensing, recommendation, multi-view learning



#### **EDUCATION**

#### PhD Mathematics & Operational Research, UNIVERSITY OF MONS, BELGIUM, (Jun 2024 – )

- > Low-rank matrix factorization, machine learning, optimization
- > Advisor: Prof. Nicolas Gillis.

#### Master

#### Artificial Intelligence, University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, Iran, (Sep 2015 – Feb 2018)

- > Thesis title: A Graph-based Semi-Supervised Learning Approach for Multi-Label Classification.
- > Advisors: Dr. Parham Moradi and Dr. Fardin Akhlaghian.
- > Courses: machine learning, statistical pattern recognition, neural networks, advanced artificial intelligence, computer vision, digital image processing, distributed systems, and fuzzy sets & systems.

#### Sofware Engineering, AMIRKABIR TECHNICAL COLLEGE, ARAK, IRAN, (Jan 2012 - Jun 2014)

> Project title: Manufacturing and Setting up a Video Conferencing Software.

#### Associate

### Computer Software, Tabriz Technical College, Tabriz, Iran, (Jan 2009 – Jun 2011)

> Supplementary courses in computer science and software engineering.



#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Thesis Advisor

#### Artificial Intelligence (graduate), University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, Iran, (Sep 2020 - Jun 2024)

- > Nine students have graduated. I am currently advising one master's student.
- > Topics: representation learning, deep learning, matrix factorization, semi-supervised learning, selfsupervised learning, robust learning, and sparse coding.
- problems: data representation, data clustering, graph clustering, recommendation systems, link prediction, and feature selection.

#### Research Assist.

#### Representation Learning, UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN, (Sep 2019 – Jun 2024)

- > Topics: matrix factorization, distributionally robust learning, generalization, and adversarial training
- > applications: image inpainting and recommendation systems.

#### Teaching Assist.

#### Artificial Intelligence (graduate), UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, (Jan 2019 – Jun 2024)

- > Advanced Concepts in Artificial Intelligence (Graduate), Spring 2023, Fall 2023
- > Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Machine Learning (Graduate), Fall 2022
- > Pattern Recognition (Graduate), Spring 2019 Spring 2023
- > Special Topics in Artificial Intelligence (Graduate), Fall 2021
- > lectures: Semi-supervised learning, Modern Machine Learning Paradigms, Nonnegative matrix factorizations, Transformer Networks

#### Lab Instructor

#### Computer Lab (undergraduate), UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN, (Fall 2019)

> I had two 14-person classes on computer basics.

AMJAD SEYEDI 1



#### **Under-Review**

#### A Unified Framework for Fair Graph Clustering with Flexible Fairness-Utility Trade-off Perspective

S. Ghodsi, A. Seyedi, T. Le Quy, F. Karimi, and E. Ntoutsi.

European Conference on Artificial Intelligence 2024 [Under-Review], June 2024.

#### Diverse Joint Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Attributed Graph Clustering

A. Mohammadi, A. Seyedi, F. Akhlaghian, and R. Pirmohamadiani.

Applied Soft Computing [Under-Review], June 2024.

#### Self-paced Elastic Nonnegative Matrix Factorization

S. Mohammadi, A. Seyedi, N. Salahian, and F. Akhlaghian.

IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing [Under-Review], March 2024.

#### 2024 | Enhancing Link Prediction through Adversarial Training in Deep Nonnegative Matrix Factorization

R. Mahmoodi, A. Seyedi, A. Abdollahpouri, and F. Akhlaghian.

Engineering Applications in Artificial Intelligence, volume 133, 2024, pp. 108641.

# Towards Cohesion-Fairness Harmony: Contrastive Regularization in Individual Fair Graph Clustering S. Ghodsi, A. Seyedi, and E. Ntoutsi.

Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 2024.

#### Orthogonal Encoder-Decoder Factorization for Unsupervised Feature Selection

M. Mozafari, A. Seyedi, R. Pirmohamadiani, and F. Akhlaghian.

Information Sciences, volume 663, 2024, pp. 120277.

#### Multi-Label Feature Selection with Global and Local Label Correlation

M. Faraji, A. Seyedi, F. Akhlaghian, and R. Mahmoodi.

Expert Systems with Applications, volume 246, 2024, pp. 123198.

#### Deep Asymmetric Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Graph Clustering

A. Hajiveiseh, A. Seyedi, and F. Akhlaghian.

Pattern Recognition, volume 148, 2024, pp. 110179.

#### 2023 Link Prediction by Adversarial Nonnegative Matrix Factorization

R. Mahmoodi, A. Seyedi, F. Akhlaghian, and A. Abdollahpouri.

Knowledge-based Systems, volume 280, 2023, pp. 110998.

#### Self-Supervised Semi-Supervised Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Data Clustering

J. Chavoshinejad, A. Seyedi, and F. Akhlaghian.

Pattern Recognition, volume 137, 2023, pp. 109282.

#### Adversarial Elastic Deep Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Matrix Completion

A. Seyedi, F. Akhlaghian, A. Lotfi, N. Salahian, and J. Chavoshinejad

Information Sciences, volume 621, 2023, pp. 562-579.

#### Deep Autoencoder-Like NMF with Contrastive Regularization and Feature Relationship Preservation

N. Salahian, F. Akhlaghian, A. Seyedi, and J. Chavoshinejad

Expert Systems with Applications, volume 214, 2023, pp. 119051.

#### 2020 Asymmetric Semi-Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Directed Graph Clustering

R. Abdollahi, A. Seyedi, and M. R. Noorimehr

IEEE International Conference on Computer and Knowledge Engineering (ICCKE), 2020, pp. 323-328.

#### 2019 | Self-Paced Multi-Label Learning with Diversity

A. Seyedi, S. S. Ghodsi, F. Akhlaghian Tab, M. Jalili, and P. Moradi

Asian Conference on Machine Learning (ACML), 2019, pp. 790-805.

#### 2018 Dynamic Graph-based Label Propagation for Density Peaks Clustering

A. Seyedi, A. Lotfi, P. Moradi, and N. N. Qader

Expert Systems with Applications, Volume 115, 2019, pp. 314-328.

#### 2017 A Weakly-Supervised Factorization Method with Dynamic Graph Embedding

A. Seyedi, P. Moradi, and F. Akhlaghian Tab

IEEE Artificial Intelligence and Signal Processing Conference (AISP), 2017, pp. 213-218.

# A Clustering-based Matrix Factorization Method to Improve the Accuracy of Recommendation Systems Z. Shajarian, A. Seyedi, and P. Moradi

IEEE Iranian Conference on Electrical Engineering (ICEE), 2017, pp. 2241-2246.

AMJAD SEYEDI

2

#### 2016 | An Improved Density Peaks Method for Data Clustering

A. Lotfi, A. Seyedi, and P. Moradi

IEEE International Conference on Computer and Knowledge Engineering (ICCKE), 2016, pp. 263-268.

# **E** COMPUTER SKILLS

Operationg Systems Microsoft Windows and Linux (ubuntu, centOS, fedora, and RedHat distributions)

Word processing & Presentation Office suites, LET<sub>E</sub>X, and Manim (animation engine for explanatory math videos)

Vector and raster softwares Adobe Illustrator, CorelDRAW, Inkscape, Adobe Photoshop, and GIMP

**Development Tools** Pycharm, Jupyter Notebook, Colab, Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, and Eclipse

Web design HTML, CSS, ASP.NET, and JavaScript

## PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

2019 – present **Python**, PyTorch, NumPy, and scikit-learn 2015 – 2020 **MATLAB**, linear algebra and visulaziation

2012 – 2015 JAVA, object-oriented software engineeing and web development

2009 – 2015 C++ | C#, Software Ebgineering and Web development

2007 – 2009 Basic | Visual Basic, Software Engineering

# 66 REFERENCES

#### Nicolas Gillis, Professor

Department of Mathematics & Operational Research University of Mons, Belgium

@ nicolas.gillis@umons.ac.be

+32 653 746 80

Parham Moradi, Associate Professor Department of Computer Engineering UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, IRAN

@ p.moradi@uok.ac.ir

+98 912 513 5478

Fardin Akhlaghian, Associate Professor Department of Computer Engineering

University of Kurdistan, Iran **@** f.akhlaghian@uok.ac.ir

+98 918 873 8383

#### Mahdi Jalili. Professor

School of Electrical and Computer Engineering RMIT University, Melbourne, Australia

@ mahdi.jalili@rmit.edu.au

+61 399 251 223

AMJAD SEYEDI 3